SUMMARY:

Bilingual coordinator with outstanding experience of administering and coordinating training programs. Highly motivated data analyst with strong quantitative skills, SPSS and STATA, experience in China issues. Possess strong communication and interpersonal skills as a bilingual writer of policy memos, announcements and research reviews.

EDUCATION:

The George Washington University, Trachtenberg school of Public Policy and Public Administration, May 2013

Master of Public Policy; concentration in program evaluation GPA: 3.7/4.0

Fudan University, Top 3 University in China July 2011

Bachelor of Arts in English Literature, Minor in Law GPA: 3.3/4.0

ACADEMIC PROJECTS:

The Urban Institute, Capstone Project: Transportation Cost Reduction for Municipal governments

- Conducted a consulting project with the GW research team and contributed a report on measures municipalities could take to reduce costs and maintain service qualities
- Collaborated with teammates to communicate with clients and scope down project topic
- Analyzed data collected from semi-structured interview and designed metrics to evaluate the impacts
- Provided oral and written reports about the final results

EXPERIENCE:

Training and Development Coordinator, U.S.-China Business and Culture Exchange Center, Oct 2014-, D.C. Program Coordinator, U.S.-China Business and Culture Exchange Center, May 2013-Sept 2014, Washington DC

- Planned, designed and facilitated interactive short-term/long-term learning sessions for 15-20 Chinese government delegations in public administration field such as higher education management, healthcare management, government communications, industry cluster and upgrade, intellectual property, etc.
- Managed the coordination, writing and production of internal and external communication plans and materials in English and in Chinese if needed, including policies, announcements, memoranda, reports, public relations and marketing plans for events and programs sponsored by UCBCEC and its U.S. and Chinese business partners
- Organized recruitment fairs that attracted more than 500 locals in Chinese community to participate requested by provinces and federal government of China
- Coordinated with media, advertising agency, Chinese community, association to create awareness for the participation of the fairs and training programs by designing posters, brochures, marketing pitches, etc.

Teaching Assistant, Center for Talented Youth, Johns Hopkins University, Feb-June 2013, Washington DC

- Tutored 17 elementary students individually outside class through Skype to help them practice oral Chinese
- Assisted teachers in maintaining good relationship with children and parents through comprehensive communication

Advocacy Assistant, Columban Center for Advocacy and Outreach, Sept-Dec 2012, Washington DC

- Monitored environmental justice issues (TPP, GMO, Jeju Island) including writing research reviews and weekly
 updates for responsible countries: China, UK, Fiji and Korea
- Drafted letters to Korean Ambassador, correspondence to Senators, action alerts and blog posts
- Advocated for Water for the World Act through scheduled meeting with the House of Representative office and educated on legislative initiatives

Research Assistant, Bridging Nations Foundation, June-August 2012, Washington DC

- Provided research reviews on energy/environment/sustainability issues, China topics, China-Indian relationship. Prepared and arranged for Indian delegation trip to China
- Wrote promotional materials for course and maintained social media streams
- Developed curriculum, course PPT presentations, for education initiative to enroll global students online

Communication Intern, Office of Shanghai Forum, April-June 2011, Shanghai, China

- Edited two issues of Newsletter of Shanghai Forum
- Translated resumes for speech guests, edited English version speech notes

Communication Intern, Bureau of Shanghai Expo Coordination, April – August 2010, Shanghai, China

- Assisted journalists with application of credentials through emails, one-on-one meetings and phone calls
- Updated and maintained database of information for credentials of journalists

ACTIVITIES:

Clinton Global Initiative University at GWU, March 2012

Leader, Volunteer association at Fudan University, Foreign Language Department, 2009-2011

People's Scholarship (top 30%) of Fudan University for 4 consecutive years, 2008-2011

Casio Sponsored Scholarship (top 30%) of Foreign Language Department, Fudan University, 2010 **SKILLS:**

Computer: Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, SPSS, STATA

Languages: Mandarin Chinese (Native Proficiency), English (Full Professional Proficiency)